Inventory of the Armistead-Cocke Papers 1680-1907
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers of Richard P. Jones and his family of, "Lands End," Gloucester County, Virginia, 1851-1863. (Box-folder 4:4-10)
  Account books and a scrapbook of poems.
  - R[ichard] P. Jones, [Lands End, Gloucester County, Virginia] farm and account book, Jan[uary] 1851- March 1854., Ms. V. (Box-folder 4:4)
  - R[ichard] P. Jones, [Lands End, Gloucester County, Virginia] farm and account book, April 1, 1854 - March 31, 1856., Ms. V. (Box-folder 4:5)
  - R[ichard] P. Jones, [Lands End, Gloucester County, Virginia] farm book, April-December 1856., Ms. V. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - R[ichard] P. Jones, [Lands End, Gloucester County, Virginia], January 1, 1857- January 31, 1861., Ms. V. (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Mr. [Hubert P.] Lefebvre's School, Richmond [Virginia], n.d., Ms. P. (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Mary Fauntleroy Jones, [1861]., Cl. V. (Box-folder 4:9)
    Re: Scrapbook of poems.
  - Richard P. Jones, Lands End, Gloucester County, Virginia, Feb[ruary] 1, 1861-July 4, 1863., Ms. V. (Box-folder 4:10)
  Series 6: Armistead-Cocke Papers - Addition 1997.34
- Armistead-Cocke Addition - Cocke and related family's papers, 1839-1916. (Othertype Acc. No. 1997.34)
  Later family letters, genealogical notes, and poems, 1839-1916, of members of the Cocke family and to related branches of Throckmorton, Curtis, Sheldon, Jones, Preston, Byrd, Dandridge, and Carter families. Includes letters kept by Elizabeth R.P. Cocke, daughter of T.L.P. Cocke and letters of Mary B. Cocke, mother of Maria C. Talcott.
  Series 7: Armistead-Cocke Papers - Addition 1998.45
- Armistead-Cocke Papers - Addition Acc. No. 1998.45, 1851-1874., ca. 300 items. (Othertype Acc. No. 1998.45)
  Includes letters of the Cocke, Curtis, and Preston families of Richmond, Virginia, particularly correspondence between Harriet Throgmorton Jones Curtis and her children Charles ("Barney"), Mary Boothe, Harriet, Maria, and Martha Curtis. Also includes correspondence between Mary Booth Curtis and her husband, Thomas Lewis Preston Cocke, as well as letters from Thomas L.P. Cocke's mother, Elizabeth R.P. Cocke, to himself and his brothers, William, Edmund, and Preston Cocke.
  - Letters from Charles C. Curtis to his mother Harriet T.J. Curtis and his sisters, 14 Nov[ember] 1869-13 Aug[ust] 1878., 39 items. (Folder 1)
  - Letters from Harriet Throgmorton Jones Curtis to her children, 27 April [18]63-21 Nov[ember] 1874., 20 items. (Folder 2)
  - Letters from Harriet Throgmorton Jones Curtis to her son, Charles Curtis, 19 Feb[ruary] 1900-24 Sept[ember] 1901., 23 items. (Folder 3)
  - Letters from Lizzie Curtis to her sisters, 25 April 1851 - n.d., 2 items. (Folder 4)
  - Letters from Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke to her sons and other family members, 19 Jan[uary] 1863[?]-8 Sept[ember] 1887., 5 items. (Folder 5)
    Letters are to her sons William F. Cocke, Thomas L.P. Cocke, Edmund R. Cocke, and Preston Cocke, and her daughters-in-law and grandchildren.
  - Correspondence between Thomas Lewis Preston Cocke and Mary Boothe Curtis Cocke, 24 Sept[ember] 1875-11 Sept[ember] 1887., 22 items. (Folder 6)
    Correspondence early in their marriage when they were apart. Includes letters from their children Maria, Harriet, Charles and William Cocke, living in Powhatan County, Virginia with their mother, to their father.
  - Letters from Harriet Curtis Cringan to her brother and other family members, 8 Nov[ember] 1886-6 September 1900., 17 items. (Folder 7)
    Letters are to brother Charles Curtis, her sisters Mary Boothe, Maria and Martha Curtis, and her brother-in-law, Thomas L.P. Cocke.
  - Letters from Martha Throgmorton Curtis James to sisters and mother, 25 April 1864-14 Oct[ober] 1895., 11 items. (Folder 8)
    Letters from Martha Throgmorton Curtis James to her sisters Mary Boothe Curtis Cocke, Maria Greenhough Curtis JOnes, Harriet Curtis Cringan, Fanny Throgmorton Curtis, and her mother Harriet T.J. Curtis, about family news.
  - Letters from Maria Greenhough Curtis to sisters and other family members, 16 Jan[uary 18]74-26 Oct[ober 18]74., 18 items. (Folder 9)
    Letters are to sisters Harriet T.J. Curtis, her brother-in-law, Thomas L.P. Cocke and her niece, Harriet Cocke.
  - Letters from Mary F. Jones to Mary Boothe Curtis, 23 Jan[uary] 1872-22 March 1875., 14 items. (Folder 10)
  - Letters from Margaret J. Preston, 4 July 1864-3 June 1892., 16 items. (Folder 11)
    Letters to her sisters, mother and Mary Booth Curtis Cocke and Thomas L.P. Cocke.
  - Letters to Mary B. Curtis, 13 April 1874-17 April 1874., 6 items. (Folder 12)
    Letters from family and friends just prior to her wedding to Thomas L.P. Cocke.
  - Miscellaneous. Letters to Charles C. Curtis, 15 items. (Folder 13)
    Letters to Curtis (also called "Barney") from friends and family.
  - Miscellaneous. Letters to Mary Booth Curtis Cocke, 7 items. (Folder 14)
    From family and friends.
  - Miscellaneous. Letters to Thomas L.P. Cocke from friends and family, 11 items. (Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous. Letters of the Curtis and Cocke families, 18 items. (Folder 16)
    Includes one photograph of Annie Page.
  - Miscellaneous. Letters of the Curtis and Cocke families, 28 items. (Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous. Academic records of William F. Cocke and Thomas P. Cocke, 6 items. (Folder 18)
    From Washington College and the University of Virginia. Also includes Vol. 1 (March 1839) of the Collegian, published by the students of the University of Virginia, and a program of the Baccalaureate Exercises at the College of William and Mary in 1935.
  - Letters from Harriet T. Jones Curtis, n.d., 6 items. (Folder 19)
    Written to her children before the Civil War.
  - Letters from Mary Boothe Curtis to her mother, sister, and Emily [?] n.d., 3 items. (Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous. Empty envelopes (Folder 21)